Jesse James Galloway Media Materials 1947-1959 PC002
Test - Paleontology Collection
Test Change Jesse James Galloway Media Materials
1947-1959
Test - Paleontology Collection
Galloway, J. J. (Jesse James), 1882-1962
PC002
3 card catalog drawers
1 tray in locked cabinet
Jesse James Galloway was a professor of Geology and Paleontology at IU from 1931-1953. Galloway’s collection consists of materials relating to foraminifera, stromatoporoids, and bryozoans.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research. Advance notice required.
Biographical Note
Galloway was a Hoosier paleontologist educated at Indiana University and is noted for having received the first PhD in Geology awarded there in 1913. Galloway studied with E.R. Cumings, first on the Indiana Ordovician sections of the Cincinnati Arch, notably the section exposed in the railway cutting at Tanners Creek, and later on strata from the rest of the state. Galloway was a pioneer in stratigraphic and industrial applications of micropaleontology and taught the first courses in micropaleontology and petroleum geology at IU.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into two series: maps and other media materials. All series are arranged according to author's organization.
Scope and Content Note
Maps, 1959, consists of Galloway's locality maps associated with The Stratigraphy and Paleontology of the Harrodsburg Limestone.
Other media materials, 1947-1956, undated, consists of prints and negatives for specimens and when Galloway was a petroleum consultant in Mexico.
Acquisition Information
Inherited from the author upon his retirement.
Foraminifera, Fossil; Stromatoporoidea; Bryozoa, Fossil; Petrology; Geology-Mexico; Geology-United States; Paleontology-Ordovician; Paleontology-Tertiary; Galloway, J. J. (Jesse James); Galloway, Jesse James
- Maps, 1959
  - Located in Cabinet AB Tray5 - Locality Maps, 1959 (Box 1)
- Other media materials, 1956; undated
  - Located in Drawer5 - 79 prints of J.J Galloway as a petroleum consultant in Mexico, undated (Box 1)
  - Located in Drawer15 - 155 sheet film negatives and 140 prints, 1948-1956 (Box 2)
    - Bryozoans film negatives and prints (Box 2)
    - Other specimen negatives and prints (Box 2)
  - Located in Drawer20 - 261 unique specimen and book prints sheet film negatives, 1950-1952 (Box 3)
    - Bryzoans sheet film negatives and prints (Box 3)
    - Crinoids sheet film negatives and prints (Box 3)
    - Trilobites sheet film negatives and prints (Box 3)
    - Other specimen sheet film negatives and prints (Box 3)
    - Book print sheet film negatives (Box 3)